SAIQA MAHBOOB

HOUSE 31, STREET 6, GULRAIZ 6, RAWALPINDI, PA KISTAN: CELL:+ 92 3365512976.SAIOA,MEHBOOB13@GMAI L.COM

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Seeking the position of a Pharmacist to gain and utilize training, knowledge and skills working towards benefiting the patients and the Healthcare Industry.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I'm a pharmacist holding a 5-year Doctor of Pharmacy (Pharm-D) degree from Islamia University of Bahawalpur, Pakistan. During my degree, I have completed two years clerkship in Clinical Pharmacy and did research on "Difference in outcomes in asthmatic patients between three ways of management of asthma (Allopathic, homeopathic and herbal) and prevalence of anemia and its management in hospitalized patients. I also have 6 months experience of working as pharmacist in different hospitals. I also worked in pharmaceutical industry 2.5 years in Export & regulatory affairs involving dossiers preparation of pharmaceutical products for export and local registrations

EDUCATION

SEPT 2008 - OCT 2013

Islamia University of Bahawalpur

Bahawalpur, Pakistan

DOCTOR OF PHARMACY (PHARM-D)

I completed this 5-year degree with an aggregate of 70% marks (3242/4650). I completed clerkship in Clinical Pharmacy during 4th and 5th Professional of Pharm-D (2011-2013) at Bahawal Victoria Hospital Bahawalpur in the areas of patient care plan, patient history, pharmacovigilance, identifying medication error, DUE/DUR and medication compliance. I also did research on "Difference in outcomes in asthmatic patients between three ways of management of asthma (Allopathic, homeopathic and herbal)" and "prevalence of anemia and its management in hospitalized patients" in 4th and 5th Professionals respectively.

WORK EXPERIENCE

NOV 2016 - PRESENT

Paramount Pharmaceuticals (Pvt) Ltd

Islamabad, Pakistan

EXPORT EXECUTIVE

- My responsibilities in the export department are related to finding customers in different countries and to do correspondence with them regarding export regulatory requirements and other export matters.
- I am also involved in preparing registration documents for Nutraceutical products registration and meeting regulatory requirements for Pharmaceutical products as well.

DEC 2015 - NOV 2016

Vision Pharmaceuticals (Pvt) Ltd

Islamabad, Pakistan

R&D AND REGULATORY PHARMACIST

- My work was related to complete product development from design input to design output. My core
 responsibility was to work on trial batches for new product development and their testing methods in close
 liaison with R&D Manager.
- My other responsibilities included preparing registration dossiers of pharmaceutical products required for export registration and local manufacturing. I also got hands-on experience in preparing export dossiers, dossiers for local registrations and other regulatory affairs documentation.

SEPT 2014 - DEC 2015

Caraway Pharmaceuticals (Pvt) Ltd

Islamabad, Pakistan

EXPORT OFFICER

My responsibilities in the export department were related to meeting regulatory compliance requirements for our pharmaceutical products. My work included preparing registration dossiers of pharmaceutical products required for export registration and local manufacturing. I also got the experience of quality control testing and documentation required in quality assurance and quality control departments.

FEB2014 - MAY 2014

Combined Military Hospital (CMH)

Rawalpindi, Pakistan

CLINICAL AND RETAIL PHARMACIST

I worked in the pharmacy of AFBMTC (Armed Forces Bone Marrow Transplant Centre). My main tasks included dispensing medication, patient counseling, stock maintenance, patient data collection and record keeping. I also took care of store stock maintenance and record keeping of stock.

DEC 2013 - JAN 2014 INTERNEE

Shifa International Hospital

Islamabad, Pakistan

 My work was related to the compounding of various dosage forms including ointments, syrups, enemas, pastes, eye drops and intravenous preparations such as hypertonic infusion under pharmacistinstructions.

PERSONAL SKILLS

| 0 | Communication Skills: I have improved my communication skills through my work experience. As an export |
|---|--|
| | executive, I dealt with clients and regulatory departments in various countries. |

| • | _ | anizational/Managerial skills: The time I have spent in the workforce and work environment has helped to equip myself with: |
|---|---|---|
| | | Strong organization skills to manage multiple timelines and complete tasks in time. |
| | | Good leadership skills, i.e. assisting juniors and co-workers with professional and personal issues. |
| | | Enthusiasm for outdoor and extra-curriculum activities. |
| | | Strong organizing and managing skills i.e work-life balance, fitting in time to assist with professional knowledge. |
| | | Increased tolerance, patience, strong communication skills as I was required to liaise with international clients. |

OTHER ACTIVITIES

- I participated in Diabetes care workshop organized by Pakistan pharmacist association and Novo Nordisk Pharma
- I was volunteer tutorial assistant for junior students.
- I attended multiple international pharmacy conferences in Lahore and Bahawalpur.

REFERENCES

Atta Ullah, R&D Manager, Vision Pharmaceuticals (Private) Limited.

Mobile: + 92 333 9277066, Email: cirin.atta@gmail.com,

Dr. M. Asadullah madni, Assistant Professor, The Islamia University of Bahawalpur.

Mobile: +92-300-6821979, Email: asadpharmacist@hotmail.com